あの方　私たちがご飯を食べ終わった時は
Sis, is that you?
姉貴か
I'm home!
ただいま
Feel free to leap into my arms!
胸に飛び込んできていいわよ
No thanks.
やめとく
Come on, I'm finally back home.
久しぶりに帰ってきたってのに
So boring.
つまんない奴
taikutsu na madobe ni
Sitting bored by the back window,
退屈な窓辺に吹き込む風に
fukikomu kaze ni
A breeze blew through the room
kao wo shikameta no wa
The reason I screwed up my eyes
顔を顰めたのは照れくさ　その裏返し
terekusasa no uragaeshi
Was to hide how embarrassed I was
Mazui Presents
Hyouka
KamiGami
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
aimai ni unazuku tenohira no kyou
I gave a faint nod from the edge of my palm
曖昧に頷く掌の今日
egaiteru jibun wa sukoshi oogesa de
The "me" I was trying to be was a bit more than I was
描いてる自分は少し大袈裟で
nani ka kawarisou na ki ga shiteiru yo
I get the feeling that something is going to change soon
何かが変わりそうな気がしているよ
kokoro ni yobikakeru kimi no sei da ne
You reached out to touch my heart; it must be because of you
心に呼びかける君のせいだね
kumorizora nozoita yokan
I had a feeling, looking into the clouds
曇り空覗いた予感
te wo nobasou itsu yori mo chikaradzuyoi yuuki de
I reached out my hand, with a stronger courage than I'd ever had
手を伸ばそう　いつよりも力強い勇気で
光も影もまだ遠くで
hikari mo kage mo mada tookute
The light and the dark are still so far away
sore demo bokura wa
But even though they are
それでも僕らは優しさの理由が知りたい
yasashisa no riyuu ga shiritai
We still want to know how people could be so kind
ima wa dare no namae demo nai
Now it doesn't matter whose name it may be
今は誰の名前でもない
kagayaki no kanata he
Beyond the horizon's light,
輝きの彼方へ
zenbu kako ni naru mae ni
Before it all becomes the past,
全部過去になる前に見つけに行こう
mitsuke ni ikou
Let's go and find out
应该拥有的东西
A present from South America?
これが南米土産か
Yeah. You wanted one, right?
そうよ　欲しかったでしょう
Not really.
別に
おはようございます
それでは　全国の天気予報…
It's pretty rare for you to watch TV.
珍しいじゃん　テレビ見てるなんて
What about the paper?
新聞は
I don't feel like thinking.
頭使いたくない
…強い勢力を持った　太平洋高気圧に覆われ　晴れるところが多くなりそうです
You look like you have some free time.
あんた　暇そうね
But I do have plans.
予定がぎっしりだ
Plans?
予定　何の
Like what?
Napping.
昼寝
I know a place where you can get 5000 yen just for sitting around.
座ってるだけで　五千円になるバイトがあるんだけど
How about it?
どう
うん
Want to do it? Maybe not?
やる　やらない
うん
Okay, that's settled then!
はい決まり
I'll tell them you'll do it.
やるってことで向こうに言っとくね
Here.
はい
You'll need it while you're working.
バイト先で使いな
…厳し熱さが続きそうです
Hello, Oreki residence.
はい折木です
Oh, Satoshi-kun? It's been a while!
あっ里志くん　久しぶり
Yeah, I just got back.
ええ　さっき戻ったとこ
Houtarou? He's here.
奉太郎　いるわよ
Just one moment.
ちょっと待っててね
Houtarou! Satoshi-kun's on the phone!
奉太郎　里志くんから電話
うん
Houtarou, did you finish reading that book I lent you?
奉太郎　前に貸した本もう読み終わったかい
うん
If you're done with it, can I get it back?
読み終わったんならそろそろ返して欲しいんだけど
うん
Mind if I come over to pick it up?
今日取りに行ってもいいかい
うん　バイトの後なら
Maybe after work.
ええ
バイトの後なら
Work? You?!
バイト　奉太郎が
What's gotten into you?!
一体なにを血迷ったんだい
Nothing really.
なんとなくな
I'm just going to be a lifeguard for the public pool at a university Sis's friend goes to.
姉貴の知り合いの代役で　市民プールの監視員だ
はあ　お姉さんの
Oh, your sister.
なるほど
I see.
It's hard to imagine you breaking a sweat.
奉太郎が額に汗するとはね
I have to go now.
もう出る時間だから切るぞ
分かった
Got it.
I'll head over later to throw some cold water on you.
後で冷やかしに行くよ
Whatever. See you.
好きにしろ
じゃな
Bye.
じゃ
Houtarou!
奉太郎
Hey, we came.
や　来たよ
I didn't think all three of you would come.
まさか三人とは思わなかった
I called them up as soon as I got off the phone with you.
あの後二人に声を掛けたんだよ
I told them they'd never get a chance to see it again.
世にも珍しいものが見られるよって
Is this what you were talking about?
福ちゃん　それがこれ
Right!
そう　働く奉太郎
Houtarou, working!
正直がっかりなんだけど
I'm not really impressed.
まあまあ　せっかくですし　皆で楽しみましょうよ
Well, it isn't every day we go to the pool. Let's have fun!
I guess, since we're here...
まあそうね　せっかくだし
Hey, you!
はいこら
Quit starin' at my woman!
人の女じろじろ見んな　ボケ
Come on, stop that!
ちょっと　止めなよ
I wasn't...
いや　そんな
お客さん　ちょっと落ち着いてください
Please calm down, sir!
なにあれ
What's up with him?
I pray I don't have to deal with them...
関わり合いになりませんように
ほら　もうちょっとだけ行くぞ
Okay, here I go!
じゃあ　行きますよ
Take that!
そーれ
Okay!
はい
Here.
Chitanda-san! Right in front of you!
千反田さん　セパタクロー
Sorry, Chii-chan.
だめね　ちーちゃん
Okay! Penalty game for Chitanda-san!
はい　千反田さん罰ゲーム
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
Here we go!
行くよ
せーの　それ
I'm going!
行くよ
Hey.
おい
It's my shift now.
交代だ
Go take a break.
休憩していいぞ
Oreki-san!
折木さん
Would you like to eat lunch together?
お昼　一緒にどうですか
I could've made a better lunch if you had told me earlier.
もうちょっと早く言ってくれてたら
もっとちゃんとした昼食作って来られたのに
Tell that to Houtarou.
それは奉太郎に言ってほしいね
Why?
どうしてですか
だって　物臭が服着て歩いているのような奉太郎がだよ
Because we're talking about Houtarou, a sloth in human clothing!
Suddenly he feels like working!
急に勤労精神に目覚めたって言うんだもん
We can't pass up seeing that.
これを見逃してはないよ
Right, Houtarou?
だろ　奉太郎
うん
It's a lot of fun getting together like this, though!
でも　こうやって皆で集まって　とても楽しいです
Well, I guess.
まあ
Either way, they just don't mix.
それにしても似合わないね
何がですか
What doesn't?
The pool and Houtarou!
プールと奉太郎
Right!
確かに
二人ともひどいですよ
Don't be so mean...
Swimming trunks and Oreki don't mix either.
水着と折木も似合わないわね
Yeah, yeah!
うんうん　太陽と奉太郎もね
And the sun and Houtarou!
The sea and Oreki!
海と折木とか
Summer and Houtarou!
夏と奉太郎とか
もう駄目ですってば
Come on, stop that!
Right, Oreki-san?
ねえ　折木さん
うん
さて　そろそろプールに戻るかな
Now then, why don't we get back to the pool?
そうね　じゃゴミ片付けようか
Yeah. I'll clean up the trash.
I'll put the chairs back.
じゃあ　椅子元に戻して置きますね
ええ　まだ欲しいの
What? You want another?
しようがないな
Well, okay then.
Let's go get you another one then.
じゃ　二つ目買いに行こっか
What a surprise.
びっくりしましたね
Yeah.
はあ
How's the job?
バイトどうですか
うん　まあ　普通
Normal, I guess.
I'd like to try it myself some day.
私も一度やってみたいです
うん
They're so fast!
速いですね
うん
Maybe he wants to be a swimmer when he grows up.
将来の夢は水泳の選手ですかね
We might have a future gold medalist in that pool right now.
あの中から　金メダルを取る選手が出てくるかも知れませんね
さあな
Who knows?
えっ
It's a simple question of whether he's someone who has the ability to or not.
そいつがそうなる人間かどうか　それだけだ
If he's special, then he will.
特別な人間ならなる　普通の人間ならならない
If he's normal, then he won't.
Do you want to be special?
折木さんは特別になりたいんですか
Not really.
別に
どの道　俺は普通の人間だ
Either way, I'm just a normal person.
You are special, Oreki-san!
折木さんは特別ですよ　私にとって
At least to me!
ええ
福部さんも摩耶花さんも特別です
Fukube-san and Mayaka-san are special too!
Everyone I meet is special to me!
私が関わった方は　私にとって皆さん特別です
That's your personal opinion.
お前の主観の話はいい　俺は一般論として
I'm talking about the public opin—
What's wrong with a personal opinion?
主観じゃ駄目ですか
You don't have to worry about being special or normal compared to everyone else!
周りと比べて　普通とか特別とか
そんなことを気にしなくだっていいじゃないですか
It doesn't matter who it is.
誰か一人でもいい　特別と思ってくれる人がいれば
So long as they think you're special, then you're special!
私はそれで十分だと思うんです
Um... I...
その　えっと
失礼します
See you later!
白露
湿冷汇聚
雨露见白也
You are special, Oreki-san!
折木さんは特別ですよ
What's wrong with a personal opinion?
主観じゃダメですか
Oreki-kun, it's my shift now.
折木くん　交代よ　休憩に入って
Take a break.
Um... Oreki-san?
あの　折木さん
うん
Um...
えっと　気になることがあるんです
There's something I'm curious about...
えっ
It's in your area of expertise.
奉太郎の仕事の範疇だよ
Do you remember that woman with the red swimsuit?
あの赤い水着の方　わかりますか
うん
When we had finished eating, she had something white on her ear.
左の耳に白いものをつけてたんです
But it's not on her ear anymore.
でも　今見たらそれがなくなってるんです
How did you notice something like that?
よくそんなことに気づいたな
I just saw it by chance.
いえ　気づいたのは本当にたまたまなんです
So? What about it?
で　それがどうした
What do you mean, "What about it?"
どうしたじゃないでしょ
もしそれがイアリングとかピアスだったらどうするの
What if it were an earring or a stub?
If someone steps on it, they might get hurt!
誰かが踏んだりしたら　最悪怪我しちゃうかもしれないのよ
Oreki-san, could you help us look for it?
折木さん　一緒に探してもらえませんか
Over the entire pool area? Are you serious?
この広さの中を　本気か
Are you sure it was on her ear?
耳についてたのは確かなのか
Yes.
はい
Then we should ask her about it before we start looking.
なら　探す前にまず本人に確認を取るべきだろう
I'd like to, but...
そうしたいんですが
It's a bit hard to ask...
なかなか聞きづらくて
It's not like you're asking anything weird.
別に変なこと聞く訳じゃない　大丈夫だろ
It'll be fine.
Then why don't you ask her?
なら　あんたが行ってきなさいよ
No thanks.
遠慮する
Please, Oreki-san!
お願いします　折木さん
Oreki, you're a lifeguard, right?
折木　あんた監視員でしょう
どうだい　奉太郎
Come on, Houtarou.
I'm curious!
私　気になります
What? That guy who was yelling?
ええ　あの怒ってた人の？
Now that's just troublesome.
面倒なことになったなあ
I don't want to make a scene, so could you look for it discreetly?
折木君　大事にしたくないからさ　こっそり探しといてよ
はあ　でも一人では無理です
But I can't do it alone.
I'll have the other lifeguards look around the poolsides.
ならほかの連中は監視回るから　プールサイドを見回ってもらおう
Could I get you to check inside the pools?
折木君　プールの中を頼むよ
I'll help you too!
私も手伝います
Me too, of course!
勿論僕も
Well, guess I will too.
ま　しょうがないわよね
Thanks.
助かる
さて　じゃあどやって探しましょうか
Okay. How should we look for it?
場所を分担した方がよさそうだね
We might want to split up and look for it.
Good idea. What do you think, Oreki-san?
そうですね　どうですか　折木さん
Up to you.
任せる
Hey, could you at least pretend to be motivated?
あんたね　ちょっとはやる気出しなさいよ
That's right! Otherwise you're getting paid for nothing.
まったくだ　まさに給料泥棒だね
At least decide how we should split up.
せめて分担くらい決めたらどうだい
Fine, I'll do it.
わかったよ　僕が考える
Chitanda-san and Mayaka handle the steps.
じゃあ　階段のところは千反田さんと摩耶花
Houtarou gets the water slide!
滑り台のところは奉太郎  飛び込み台のところは僕
And I'll take the diving board!
What do you think?
で　どうかな
Okay!
わかりました
Sounds good to me.
いいんじゃない
頼む
Good luck.
奉太郎
Houtarou.
Is this job something you have to do?
このバイトって　やるべきことなのかい
Who knows?
どうだろう
What, you never gave it any thought?
なんだ　考えてないの？
What's your motto even for then?
なんともお粗末なモットーだねえ
Well, sorry.
悪かったな
Right. There you go.
そう　それ
At least complain or something.
文句でもなんでも　リアクションはしてくれないとね
You have to respond when people talk to you.
You're boring otherwise.
つまんないよ
See you in a bit, then.
じゃあね　またあとで
Oreki.
折木
Quit slacking.
サボってんじゃないわよ
I'm not slacking.
サボってない
I found a marble, so I came here to throw it away.
お弾きを拾ってたから　捨てに来ただけだ
Oh, really?
どうだか
I'm getting depressed just looking at you.
折木　今のあんた見てると力抜けちゃうのよね
Frankly, it's annoying.
はっきり言って　迷惑
Then stop looking at me.
なら　見るな
Before, I'd only get pissed off looking at you.
前のあんたは見てるとイライラしてたのよね　それも迷惑
That was annoying too.
You're annoying either way, so at the very least, be more like the old you.
どっちも迷惑なんだけどさ
だったら　せめて前のあんたに戻ってよね
はり合いあるだけ　まだましだからさ
It was better when you had some fight in you.
Better, huh?
まだまし… か
Did you find it?
見つかったの？
No, but we might not need to look for it.
いや　でも　探さなくてもよくなるかもしれん
Does that mean you've figured something out?
ということは　奉太郎　何か分かったんだね
It's okay.
大丈夫だ
Chitanda, did you really see an earring?
千反田　お前が見たのは本当にイアリングか
Not clearly...
はっきりとは　ただ左の耳に白いものがあったのは確かです
I just remember that there was something white on one of her ears.
片方だけというなら　ピアスかもしれないわね
If it was only on one side, then it might be a stub.
No.
違う　装飾品の種類を聞いてるんじゃない
I'm not asking about the kind of accessory.
I'm asking if what she saw was an accessory in the first place.
ついてたのはそもそも装飾品なのかってことだ
What do you mean?
どういうこと？
Look at that.
あれを見てくれ
If she were wearing something on her ear,
もし耳に何かをつけているんだとしたら
she wouldn't just hit her ears like that.
あんなふうに無造作に耳を叩かないんじゃないか
Which means?
つまり？
Whatever was on her ear had to get on there without her noticing.
耳についていたのは　おそらく本人が知らないうちについた何かだ
だとしたら　何がついてたっていうの？
But then what was on her ear?
Well...
それなんだが
Satoshi, could you carry Ibara in your arms?
里志　伊原を抱っこしてくれるか
Sure.
こんなところで！？
In a place like this?!
Then what about Chitanda?
じゃあ　千反田ならどうだ？
ちーちゃんだからいいってわけないでしょう
The problem isn't who's holding me!
It'll be like I'm a little kid! It's embarrassing!
小さい子供みたいだ　恥ずかしいじゃない
Well, that's because I want to see how a little kid would do it.
まあ　まさに小さい子供の予想を試したいからなんだが
And why do I have to do that anyway?
大体　何のためにそんなことするのよ
To prove my theory.
仮説の裏づけだ
By theory, you mean this case?
仮説って　この件の？
Yeah.
I don't mind.
私は構いませんよ
Okay, fine! I'll do it!
わかったわよ　やればいいんでしょう
千反田さん　結構力持ちだね
You're pretty strong, Chitanda-san.
What's that supposed to mean?
どういう意味
I didn't mean it like that!
いや　そういう意味じゃないって
That's just the way it looks.
あくまで一般的な見方としてだよ
I thought so.
やっぱり
What do you mean?
やっぱりって　何がです？
Her hands.
手だ　普通は肩に置く
You'd usually put them on the shoulders.
Hey, can I get down now?
ねえ　もう降りていい
Yeah. Go ahead.
あ　構わない
Look at that.
あれを見てくれ
I saw that woman holding that little kid earlier.
さっき　あの女性があの子を抱っこしているところを見かけた
I'm guessing they're mother and son.
二人は多分親子かなんかだろう
Now, what would happen if she held that kid while he was holding ice cream?
あの子がソフトクリームを持ったまま抱っこされたらどうなるかだが
I see!
そうか　ちょうど耳のところにソフトクリームがあたりそうだね
The ice cream could touch her ear just like that!
Exactly.
ということだ
Then it's not on her ear now because...
じゃ　今それがないのは
...it came off while she was swimming, or someone told her.
泳いでるうちに落ちたか　誰かに教えてもらったか
Something like that.
そんなとこだろう
あ　あの　折木さん
Um... Oreki-san!
What now?
どうした
Um... I...
えっと　その
I think that how you do that is amazing!
私　折木さんのそういうところ　やっぱりすごいと思います
Flattery's not going to get you anything.
褒めても何も出んぞ
Okay!
はい
It's been a while since we've seen you so cynical.
なんか久しぶりだねえ　奉太郎の皮肉
Is that bad?
悪いか
Definitely bad.
悪いね　ないとこっちが調子狂っちゃうからねえ
It's hard to know what to do when you're not.
Oh, right! I haven't had a chance to thank you yet.
そうだ　まだお礼を言ってませんでした
Oreki-san, thank you very much.
折木さん　どうもありがとうございました
Sorry to cause you so much trouble.
お騒がせして　すみませんでした
It's fine...
ああ　いや
Chii-chan, don't!
ちーちゃん　違うわ
イアリングがピアスって言ったのは私だもの
I'm the one who said it could have been an earring or stub.
Sorry, Oreki.
折木ごめん
It's okay. Just stop it.
いいから　やめろ
Alright! Now that that's over, I'm getting kind of hungry.
さーて　一息ついたら　なんか小腹がすいてきたな
僕もソフトクリーム
Maybe I'll get some ice cream—
What about ice cream—
ソフトクリームがどうし…あ　氷菓
Oh! Hyouka!
福ちゃん　氷菓の原稿　今度こそ間違いなく明日くれるって言ったのよね
Fuku-chan!
Yesterday, you said you'd definitely have your manuscript done by today!
So, is it done?
どうなの　もう出来てるの
Well, it's kind of done, but not really...
まあ　大体できてるというか　なんというか
That means it's not done yet!
要するに出来てないのね　そうなのね
Right?
That's one way to put it...
そうともいうかなあ
そうとしか言わないわよ
It's the only way to put it!
はい　福ちゃん　今すぐ帰って原稿書くわよ
Fuku-chan, we're going back, and you're finishing your manuscript!
今日という今日は仕上がるまで絶対放さないんだから
I'm not letting you go until you're completely done with it today!
It's just a little more!
やあ　あともう少しだから　一人でも頑張れるよ
I can finish it on my own!
信用できない
You think I'll believe that?
Chii-chan, Oreki, sorry!
ちーちゃん　折木　ごめん
We're going back now.
先帰るね　また明日
See you tomorrow.
Goodbye—
さような…
I hope they can finish that manuscript.
原稿仕上がるといいですね
Who knows?
どうだかな
Well, they say life is good when someone needs you.
ま　求められてるうちがはなだ　精々頑張ればいいさ
Best of luck either way.
When you can need someone...
求められるうち
It looks like I needed you today.
私　今日の折木さんに頼ってしまいましたね
Thank you again.
いつもすみません
Seriously. It was a real pain.
まったくだ　いい迷惑だ
That was mean...
ひどいです
But, you know...
でも　まあ　それも悪くないかな
that might not be so bad.
No, nothing.
いや　なんでもない
そういえば　折木さん
Oh, by the way, Oreki-san,
how did you know that the white thing was ice cream?
白いもの　どうしてソフトクリームってわかったんですか
Oh, that? That was easy.
あ　それか
簡単だ　ここにはほかに白いものはない
There isn't anything white around here but that.
Well, I guess there's one other thing.
もうひとつあったか
I think I should go now too.
じゃあ　私もこれで
Have fun with the rest of your work.
バイト　頑張ってくださいね
S-Sure.
Hey!
おい　交代だ
It's your shift now.
Sure...
はい
What a pain.
面倒くさ
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
まどろみの約束
mebaeteta nukumori atatakakute tomadou
I felt a growing warmth; it felt so nice that I couldn’t think
芽生えてた温もり　暖かくて戸惑う
konna kimochi wo mada anata wa wakaranai no
But these feelings I have, you still don’t know they’re here
こんな気持ちをまだ　あなたは分からないよ
sono shisen ni wa imi nante betsu ni nai hazu
I don’t think there’s anything special in how you look at me
そんな視線には意味なんて　別にないはず
datte tomodachi ni shiteru no to onaji
It’s the same way you look at your friends
だって友達にしてるのと同じ
akegata ni kieteku chiisana negaiboshi
Fading into the dawn, my tiny wishing star
明け方に消えてく　小さな願星
yoru no aida de no mahou
Magic that lasts only the night
夜の間だけの魔法を…
konya koi ni kawaru
Tonight’s the night we fall in love
今夜恋に変わる　幸せな夢で会おう
shiawase na yume de aou
Let’s meet in our sweet dreams
kitto ne mitsukete ne
Please come and find me
きっと　ねぇ見つけてね
madoromi no yakusoku
A promise for when we sleep
まどろみの約束